<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Claudio Noguera</title>
    <link>https://frosklis.tk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Claudio Noguera</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-es</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 19:41:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://frosklis.tk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Delivering gifts (Kaggle)</title>
        <link>https://frosklis.tk/posts/delivering-gifts-kaggle/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://frosklis.tk/posts/delivering-gifts-kaggle/</guid>
        <description>Claudio Noguera https://frosklis.tk/posts/delivering-gifts-kaggle/ -&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things we take for granted. One of these things is logistics. We assume that when we have one order delivered it will arrive on time, but we often overlook how difficult it actually is. Well, there was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/c/santas-stolen-sleigh&#34; title=&#34;Santa&#39;s stolen sleigh&#34;&gt;Kaggle competition just about that&lt;/a&gt;. And they just made it harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The [travelling salesman problem] is perhaps the best known NP problem. Given a set of cities, the goal is to find the shortest route that goes through all the cities. The only way to assure a solution is optimal, in general, is actually trying all the possible solutions. But &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com&#34; title=&#34;Kaggle&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; made it even harder. In the Kaggle problem Santa Claus has a lot of gifts (100,000) to give. Each give has a weight and a location to be sent to. The deers get tired because of the distance and the weight they carry. The sleight itself also has a weight and a load limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is first to load the sleigh, then deliver the gifts, go back to the North Pole and repeat until all gifts are delivered. The second part is in itself an NP-hard problem, even harder than the TSP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of going from A to B is not static&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It depends on the distance from A to B and the weight of the sleigh plus the gifts&amp;hellip; and the weight of the sleigh depends on the order of the previously visited cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and the first part - loading the sleigh - somehow resembles another NP-hard problem: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knapsack_problem&#34; title=&#34;Knapsack problem&#34;&gt;the knapsack problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best approach I could think of involves reconstructing the trip backwards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start from the North Pole, with an empty sleigh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose the next city to visit and load the sleigh. If the sleigh is too loaded, it has to go back to the North Pole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat until all cities have been visited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that gives a solution that is O-A-B-O-C-D-O, the actual solution is that reversed (O-D-C-O-B-A-O): two trips, one with gifts AB and another with CD. I did it this way because doing that I can avoid taking the decision of what cities to visit in each trip in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is, however, one big caveat: there are 100,000 gifts. This means that operationally I cannot address the full problema at once. SO what I did was start with a logical solution: grouping gifts that are close. Once I have that I optimize de rout using ant colony optimization. And then more or less randomly satrt merging trips to see if I can find a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, that method gets me a bad position in the contest but with 2% of the winner&amp;rsquo;s solution. Still two days to go.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://frosklis.tk/posts/delivering-gifts-kaggle/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Inbox zero</title>
        <link>https://frosklis.tk/posts/inbox-zero/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://frosklis.tk/posts/inbox-zero/</guid>
        <description>Claudio Noguera https://frosklis.tk/posts/inbox-zero/ -&lt;p&gt;Despite a lot of hype saying email is broken, I just do not agree. I take pride in going through every email that comes to me. I do the same with the RSS subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is a catch: I do not read it all. I quickly go through the email and - if it is an automated email - I just press &amp;ldquo;j&amp;rdquo; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mail.google.com/&#34; title=&#34;Gmail&#34;&gt;gmail&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.feedly.com/&#34; title=&#34;feedly&#34;&gt;feedly&lt;/a&gt;) or the down arrow in my work mail and go to the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a typical day (not including spam) I get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;about 10 emails I do need to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;about 100 emails I do not need to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;120 new posts from my RSS sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To pin emails I do need to reread I trust in &lt;a href=&#34;https://inbox.google.com/&#34; title=&#34;Inbox by Gmail&#34;&gt;inbox&lt;/a&gt; by google (so great in the phone!) and outlook in my work laptop. They both have a wonderful functionality: set reminders to your emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the posts, if I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to read through an interesting article, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getpocket.com&#34; title=&#34;Pocket&#34;&gt;pocket&lt;/a&gt; (I also use it in regular web browsing)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy with the way I handle that, but I can do better. I am trying to unsubscribe from most marketing lists, set apps not to notify me via email and that kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://frosklis.tk/posts/inbox-zero/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Indonesia</title>
        <link>https://frosklis.tk/posts/indonesia/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://frosklis.tk/posts/indonesia/</guid>
        <description>Claudio Noguera https://frosklis.tk/posts/indonesia/ -&lt;p&gt;My next big trip will be to Indonesia, where I will go with my girlfriend (you will be able to follow the trip in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kmc2.tk&#34;&gt;our blog&lt;/a&gt;. It will be the farthest I’ve ever been from my home country - Spain. Going far away is a big factor on making a trip memorable. This will be some 12,000 km away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indonesia is very different to any other country I have been to, some firsts will happen there . It will be the first time in South East Asia, but this country is so big it touches Oceania. It will also be my first time in the southern hemisphere - it will be winter there, but being so close to the equator we won’t notice. But Indonesia is not only different for me, it is unique on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more than 200 million people, it is the biggest muslim country in the world, although religion there is not so strict as in other worlds, it is kind of mixed with ancestral tribal rituals that make it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the biggest island country. That one is easy, as there are not many island countries in the world (the UK, New Zealand, Madagascar and then small island - countries), but it is BIG, about four times the size of Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From farthest west to farthest east it is more than 3,000 km, that is comparable to the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the country with most volcanoes on Earth, some of them are active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, compared to Spain, it is a poor country. Infrastructures are not first world class, no good road network, incredible traffic and strange flight schedules. When I say strange flight schedules I mean there are a lot of local flight companies that do not guarantee that the flight will even take off. This annoyance is making the trip hard to organize. It is easy to get there either to Jakarta or Bali, as there are international connections with big airlines but flying locally - as we will do - is difficult to arrange:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight companies don’t accept Visa, MasterCard, American Express or Paypal… so you have to book through an agency or have someone there pick up the tickets for you. When you do buy a flight, it is not automatic. You first book it, then you are given the confirmation, a process which takes days. Another thing is visas. You can get visas in the airport, which is convenient, but not in all of them so we may end getting our visas from the embassy (as we may take an internal flight just when we arrive). Interestingly, this is more expensive (almost double, 35€ vs $20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I enjoy this part of traveling - arrangements. But I wouldn’t go through all the hassle if it weren’t for the good parts of Indonesia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being able to say I was there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Bali, which sounds really exotic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeing the Indian Ocean, which I haven’t seen. Honestly, I don’t know yet if there is Pacific Ocean coast as well, that would make it two oceans I have never seen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incredible scenery - volcanoes, beaches and jungle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strange ancient constructions, with a lot of temples worth a visit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See how people live over there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll see how it goes :)&lt;/p&gt;
- https://frosklis.tk/posts/indonesia/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Thousand BHP in Formula 1?</title>
        <link>https://frosklis.tk/posts/thousand-bhp-in-formula-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://frosklis.tk/posts/thousand-bhp-in-formula-1/</guid>
        <description>Claudio Noguera https://frosklis.tk/posts/thousand-bhp-in-formula-1/ -&lt;p&gt;With the new &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;regulation of Formula 1&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, an emphasis has been put in cost reduction and hybrid technology development. I think it is far too regulated and do not really believe that a cost reduction has been achieved (though I do no have data to back it up). Anyway, thousand horsepower?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is a psychological barrier and honestly, difficult to answer. Right now, F1 cars do not have engines, they have &amp;ldquo;power units&amp;rdquo;. The power unit has a traditional 6-cylinder atmospheric combustion engine, a battery, and an electrical engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s make some numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Petrol has around 45,000 kJ/kg. Say F1 cars can get special petrol, so 50,000 kJ/kg. With the current regulations, fuel flow is limited to 100 kg/h (article 5.1.4). That yields 5,000,000 kJ/h. A Watt is one Joule per second and one horse power is 735 Watts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So 5,000,000 / 3600 = 1388 kW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUT. That is thermal power, the amount of mechanical power that can be extracted from thermal power is limited by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Carnot&amp;rsquo;s theorem&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. For power plants that produce electricity that is around 35%. For a car it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even reach 20%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1388 x 0.2 = 278 kW = 378 horse power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That gives only &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;378 horse power&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; for the combustion engine in the power unit. I have been generous with the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the electrical part. Electrical energy can be converted to mechanical energy with almost no loss, so I will assume 100% efficiency. According to regulations (article 5.2.3), the torque is limited to 200 Nm and the revolutions to 50,000 rpm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;200 Nm x 50,000 rpm = 167 kW&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;167 kW from the electrical part + 278 kW from the combustion part = 445 kW = approx 600 horsepower, very far from both 1,000 horsepower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One answer and one question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No, I do not see thousand horse power happening, unless the maximum flow rate is increased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2015 F1 cars are reported to have around 850 horse power. Where do they come from? Someone please explain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://frosklis.tk/posts/thousand-bhp-in-formula-1/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Jekyll is so nice!</title>
        <link>https://frosklis.tk/posts/jekyll-is-so-nice/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://frosklis.tk/posts/jekyll-is-so-nice/</guid>
        <description>Claudio Noguera https://frosklis.tk/posts/jekyll-is-so-nice/ -&lt;p&gt;I have moved my blog from a custom based solution to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34; title=&#34;jekyll&#34;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. What I was using was &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/appengine/&#34; title=&#34;Google App Engine&#34;&gt;appengine&lt;/a&gt; and before that I had used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wordpress.org/&#34; title=&#34;Wordpress&#34;&gt;wordpress&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wordpress doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you too much control. Of course you can configure it but it is so hard to do, I find PHP a nightmare and Wordpress&amp;rsquo; API difficult to interact with. It was a pain doing plugins. It has one big advange though: it is easy to use for any user. They have done a great job doing that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I moved to Google&amp;rsquo;s app engine. You can check the blog I have with my girlfriend there, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kmc2.tk/&#34; title=&#34;km c2&#34;&gt;kmc2&lt;/a&gt;. It is so much nicer to program because you get to use python and you can control absolutely evrything. It is a really powerful tool and simpler to use than &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/&#34; title=&#34;Amazon Web Services&#34;&gt;aws&lt;/a&gt;. Managing users and providing a user interface &lt;em&gt;ala Wordpress&lt;/em&gt; was difficult to program but I learned a lot of python, html, css and javascript during the process. Specially the python part is helping my in my job (I do have one!) as a data scientist, as my scripting abilities have improved a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34; title=&#34;jekyll&#34;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I am not going to migrate to jekyll my other blog (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kmc2.tk/&#34; title=&#34;km c2&#34;&gt;kmc2&lt;/a&gt;), at least no any time soon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be a lot of work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would have to teach my girlfriend how to use it and it is difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult but so easy at the same time. Provided you know git and are not affraid of command lines, there is nothing new to learn. Right to my workflow is: I (create a new post)[https://jekyllrb.com/docs/posts/] in a plain text file with a text editor (I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sublimetext.com/&#34; title=&#34;sublime text&#34;&gt;sublime&lt;/a&gt;), add it to the repo and commit it. Done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something goind behind the scene. I created a post-commit hook that takes advantage of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parse.com/&#34; title=&#34;parse&#34;&gt;parse&lt;/a&gt; command line tools so that when I commit the site is generated and uploaded to parse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My post-commit hook:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is so nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update 2019: I now use [hugo], which is even better. Using it already for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kmc2.tk/&#34; title=&#34;km c2&#34;&gt;kmc2&lt;/a&gt; and here too.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://frosklis.tk/posts/jekyll-is-so-nice/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>P2P lending</title>
        <link>https://frosklis.tk/posts/p2p-lending/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://frosklis.tk/posts/p2p-lending/</guid>
        <description>Claudio Noguera https://frosklis.tk/posts/p2p-lending/ -&lt;p&gt;I like my savings to produce more money. At least I try with, currently, bad results. However I do follow the golden rule of not risking money you really need. I have explored a lot of options in the past such as shares, investment funds or even derivatives such as warrants and CFDs. Overall, I have lost money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I have lost it because I really hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken it seriously. It is a full time job and requires a lot of studying&amp;hellip; or a lot of good luck. Not the case. I just do not have the time nor the will power to dedicate myself to shares tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I heard about P2P lending, which is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potentially lucrative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The business model is simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone needs a loan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of asking a bank for the money he asks form money in a lending platform (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bondora.ee/&#34; title=&#34;Bondora&#34;&gt;Bondora&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comunitae.es/&#34; title=&#34;Comunitae&#34;&gt;Comunitae&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The loan goes through an auction processs, where other people (me!) finance a small part of the loan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once everything is funded, the loan starts to get paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is simple, just like a bank, but with the power of crowdsourcing. This enables people who need money to have access to it because a bank may not find them suitable and people with money to get a better return than bonds. The risk is of course that people may not pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some money in both &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bondora.ee/&#34; title=&#34;Bondora&#34;&gt;Bondora&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comunitae.es/&#34; title=&#34;Comunitae&#34;&gt;Comunitae&lt;/a&gt;, with mixed results. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bondora.ee/&#34; title=&#34;Bondora&#34;&gt;Bondora&lt;/a&gt; allows you to invest from as low as 5€, which is really good for diversification and also gives higher returns. However, I have seen my profitability reduces by a lot of people that just do not pay; when that happens, they are kindly asked to pay before pursuing legal action but - honestly - I do not expect to get any of that money.
The problem is so big that three values of profitability are given: conservative, moderate and optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current conservative expected profitability: 17,75% annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not bad, but I am starting to like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comunitae.es/&#34; title=&#34;Comunitae&#34;&gt;Comunitae&lt;/a&gt; better. You have to invest from 50€ on, so it is worse for diversification, but so far a I have experienced less unpaid loans. I am less diversified here, so profitability expectations range from 3% to 19% annually.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://frosklis.tk/posts/p2p-lending/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Movistar DNS</title>
        <link>https://frosklis.tk/posts/movistar-dns/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://frosklis.tk/posts/movistar-dns/</guid>
        <description>Claudio Noguera https://frosklis.tk/posts/movistar-dns/ -&lt;p&gt;I had been suffering connection issues lately which made the internet feel slow. Frustrating, as I have a 100 Mbps FTTH connection. The problem is the DNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/speed/public-dns/&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s DNS&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.8.8.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.8.4.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point I decided I should use Movistar&amp;rsquo;s own DNS because it pings in about 5ms, which is good, so I added them to my DNSs. However they are not reliable at all. I can only guess that the OS chooses the DNS based on their ping (&lt;em&gt;any help? How do Macs do it?&lt;/em&gt;). The solution, remove them and stick to the Google ones. Although they ping in about 40ms (8x slower, this is because I am in Europe), they seem to be more reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://frosklis.tk/posts/movistar-dns/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Converting DNG to jpeg</title>
        <link>https://frosklis.tk/posts/converting-dng-to-jpg/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://frosklis.tk/posts/converting-dng-to-jpg/</guid>
        <description>Claudio Noguera https://frosklis.tk/posts/converting-dng-to-jpg/ -&lt;p&gt;I shoot most of my pictures in RAW with my Nikon D90. Once I transfer them to my computer, I change the format to DNG (I am not sure if this is useful or not, but NEF is Nikon&amp;rsquo;s proprietary format whereas DNG is standard, backed by Adobe and -in theory- future proof). However, raw formats are not useful for quick previewing and most machines do not support it natively (Macs do support it, though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then all my pictures are kept in a hard drive that syncs to some computers using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bittorrent.com/sync/&#34;&gt;bittorrent sync&lt;/a&gt;. One of the copies is a HTPC that I have connected to my home TV, so it serves both as a backup in case the hard drive where the pictures are kept is lost or stolen and as a way to see them comfortably in the TV. This is where a script that transforms raw images into jpeg comes handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cybercom.net/~dcoffin/dcraw/&#34;&gt;dcraw&lt;/a&gt; and I have used info from &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/8699293/how-to-monitor-a-complete-directory-tree-for-changes-in-linux&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mutaku.com/wp/index.php/2011/02/cook-your-raw-photos-into-jpeg-with-linux/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/frosklis/466a77f2c9972990a141&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. There are things missing, such as real file change monitoring, but it gets the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
- https://frosklis.tk/posts/converting-dng-to-jpg/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>So I have a blog</title>
        <link>https://frosklis.tk/posts/so-i-have-a-blog/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://frosklis.tk/posts/so-i-have-a-blog/</guid>
        <description>Claudio Noguera https://frosklis.tk/posts/so-i-have-a-blog/ -&lt;p&gt;A lot of times have I started some kind of blog. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kmc2.tk&#34;&gt;have one already&lt;/a&gt; together with my girlfriend where we write about our trips. I used to have one while at university where I talked about the restaurants where we had lunch. I have an account in a lot of services. But a blog as such where I wrote whatever came to my mind and in English, it is a first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this is a personal blog, I will write about whatever I want. I like the idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edans.es&#34;&gt;Enrique Dans&lt;/a&gt;, that he uses his blog as a place to prepare his classes. It is not that I am a teacher, but I read a lot of stuff and sometimes I find it interesting and like to take notes about it. Having them easily accesible is a very valuable resource for myself. If others like it, even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could say there are tools for that, say &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evernote.com&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; for example, but they are not as fun as coding the blog / website yourself. Eventually the code will be free software, once I feel it is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, the title of this entry is not original at all. I took it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig.csail.mit.edu/breadcrumbs/node/38&#34;&gt;Tim Berners Lee&amp;rsquo;s first post in his blog&lt;/a&gt; He invented the hyperlink. Respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you!&lt;/p&gt;
- https://frosklis.tk/posts/so-i-have-a-blog/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 